Previously on AMC's The Walking Dead...
- 가브리엘 입니다
- 교회가 있다고 했지?
- Gabriel...
- You said you had a church.
난 이 남자를 믿지 않아
뭔가 숨기는게 있어
I don't trust this guy.
He's hiding something.
이곳이 푸드뱅크 였어요
온 동네에 배식을 했었죠
This was the food bank.
Served the whole county.
- 가브리엘을 지켜야 해
- 무슨일이에요?
- We have to get Gabriel.
- What happened?
나도 모르겠어
I don't know.
이제 우리가 유진을 워싱턴으로 데려가면
그가 좀비들을 끝낼 수 있어요
We get Eugene to Washington,
and he will make the dead die
그리고 살아있는 사람들이
세상을 다시 차지할 것 입니다
and the living will have
this world again.
함께 하지!
해 보자구
We're in!
Let's do it.
좋은 소식은
네가 아직 죽지 않았단 거지
Good news is, you're not dead.
하지만 결국에는
But at the end of the day,
잡아 먹힐거야
a man's got to eat.
(breathing rapidly)
이곳에 머무는건
좀 어리석은 짓이지
Gareth: It's probably
pretty stupid to be here.
위험하기도 하고
Dangerous.
아닐 수도 있겠지
뭐 난 모르겠어
I don't know, maybe not.
(snarling)
너도 위협을 느꼈을거야
You can see the threat.
그게 말할 수 없는 무언가겠지
That's something.
저것들을 보고 있노라면
기분이 좋아져
Looking at them makes me
feel better about things.
엄마는 땅 위에 있는 것 만으로도
승리하는 거라고 말했지
My mom used to say that every
day above ground was a win.
쉽게 빗댈 순 없겠지만...
Doesn't really
apply anymore, but...
그 말을 잘 생각해 보라고
you can still get
some perspective.
이 유리는 조만간 깨질거야
The glass is gonna break
sooner or later.
오래 버틸 수 있는 건
이제 아무것도 없어
Nothing lasts too long anymore.
그거 알아? 우리가 여기까지
표시를 해놨던 건
You know, we marked our way here
우리가 돌아갈 길을
쉽게 찾으려고 그랬던거야
so that we could find
our way back after.
참 바보같지 않나?
그러니까...
So stupid, right?
I mean...
뭐 어디로 돌아갈건데?
back to what?
단순히 함정은 아니었어
선택할 수 있었지
It wasn't just a trap.
It was gonna be a choice.
우리와 함께 할 수도
아님 우리에게 먹힐 수도 있었지
You join us or feed us.
그거아나?
You know...
곰들은 말야...
bears...
굶주리기 시작하면
자기들 새끼를 잡아먹어
when they start to starve,
they eat their young.
만약 어른 곰이 죽게되면
새끼는 어쨌든 죽게 되잖나
If the bear dies,
the cub dies anyway.
하지만 만약에 곰이
살 수 있다고 생각해 봐
But if the bear lives,
그 곰은 언제라도 다른 새끼를
낳을 수 있게 되는 거지
it can always have another cub.
그게 방식이야
That was part of the pitch.
있지 그렉과 마이크가
You know, Greg and Mike
came this close
우리 엄마를 죽인 그 회색머리년을
거의 잡기 직전까지 갔었는데
to nabbing that grey-haired
queen bitch who killed my mom.
그 년이 활쟁이와 차를 타고 떠났다더군
She drove away with the archer.
그렉이 그걸 봤지
Greg saw them pull away.
먹고 싶어 미치겠구만
Can't wait to try her.
난 여자가 더 맛있더라
I like women better.
우리 대부분이 그렇게 생각하지
Most of us do.
내 동생 알렉스는...
My brother Alex has--
지금은 릭 때문에 죽었지만 말야
also currently dead
because of Rick--
여자한테는 지방 층이 더 있어서
더 맛있다고 믿었었지
he had a theory that it was
because of the extra layer of fat
여자들은 출산하니까 뭐 좀 다른 게 있잖아
that women have, you know,
for childbearing.
심지어 마른 여자들도 그런게 있으니까
Even the skinny girls have it.
그 잘 빠진 애같이 말야
사샤랬나?
Like that pretty one--
Sasha?
내 생각엔 그렇게 이쁜 애들이
더 맛있는 것 같아
I think pretty people
taste better, too.
우린 너희들 다 잡으러 갈거야
We're going to get all of them.
그래도 전채요리로
너 정도면 충분하지
But for starters,
you'll do just fine.
네 다리는 작업이 잘 됐어
We did a good job on your leg.
연습을 했었거든
- (sobbing)
- We've had practice.
우리가 막 시작했을 땐
천천히 죽이는 법을 배웠어
When we started, it was
about making it slow.
내가 이렇게 인간답게
말해주고 있잖아
I'm being a human being here.
I'm talking to you.
좋게 생각하라구, 밥
Perspective, Bob.
넌 아직 땅 위에 있잖아
You're above ground.
적어도 넌 저것들 보단 낫잖나
At least you're
better off than them.
(laughing)
이젠 실성했구만
Well, he lost it.
내가 생각했던 것보단
오래 버텼어
Lasted longer than
I thought he would.
(laughing continues)
너희들...
You...
이 병신새끼들
you idiots.
알겠어, 침착하라구
- Okay, keep it down.
- (pounding on glass)
내가 입 다물게 할 수도 있어
I can shut him up.
나를 뜯어먹고 있었구나
이 병신같은 자식들아!
I've been bitten,
you stupid pricks!
난 감염된 고깃덩이지롱
I'm tainted meat.
- (laughing)
- (spitting)
- 그냥 지금 죽여버리자
- 아니 안돼, 쓸모가 있어
- Let's just kill him now.
- No, no, we need him.
지금껏 저런 놈들 먹고 있었을지도 몰라
We might as well
be eating one of them.
대체 이제 어떻게 되는거야?
What the hell's gonna happen?
우리도 변하는거야?
우리도 죽는거야?
Are we gonna turn?
Are we just gonna die?
알버트, 제발 진정좀 해
우린 익혀서 먹었어
Albert, calm the hell down.
We cooked him.
다 괜찮을거야
Everything is gonna be fine.
왜 먼저 확인하지 않은 거야?
Why the hell didn't
you check him first?
그땐 괜찮았으니까
'Cause he was fine.
- 감염됐지롱!
- 닥쳐
- Tainted meat!
- Gareth: Shut up.
- 너넨 감염된 고기를 먹은거야!
- 닥치라고!
- You eating tainted meat!
- I said shut up!
(theme music playing)
한글자막 워키토끼
수정 금지 / 배포 제한상업적 이용 금지
본 저작물의 저작권은 원저작권자 미국 AMC와 FOX사에 있습니다
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
밥
(whispering) Bob.
(panting)
(snarling)
(twig snaps)
- (snarling)
- (gasps)
(silenced gunshot)
나야 나라고
- (muffled scream)
- It's me. It's me.
오빠
Tyreese.
- 그가 떠났어
- 누가?
- He's getting away.
- Who?
누군가 우릴 보고 있었어
Somebody was watching us.
지금 저곳으로 들어가면
If we go in there now,
다시 같이 돌아올 수 없을거야
some of us aren't coming back.
밥이 저 어딘가로 나갔어
Bob is out there somewhere.
겁에 질렸을거야 혼자
Scared, alone.
혼자있는게 아닐 수도 있어
Maybe not alone.
데릴과 캐롤도 사라졌어
Daryl and Carol
are missing, too.
(silverware clattering)
(doors open)
그만하시죠
Stop.
지금 뭘 하는 겁니까?
What are you doing?
지금 무슨 일을 꾸미고 있는 거냐구요
모든게 연관되어 있어
This is all connected.
당신이 나타나고
You show up,
우린 감시 당했어
we're being watched,
그 와중에 우리 중 셋이 사라졌고
and now three of us are gone.
저는...
I...
저는 아무것도...
I don't...
이건 제가 꾸민 일이 아니에요
I don't have anything
to do with this.
- 잠깐만요!
- 그러지마!
- Wait!
- Rosita: Don't!
- 사샤 그 칼 치워
- 밖에 있는게 누구야?
- Tyreese: Sasha, put it away.
- Who's out there?
저, 저는 정말 아무것도...
I-- I don't have
anything...
- 저랑은 관련이 없어요
- 우리 사람들은 어디있지?
- to do with this.
- Where are our people?
- 저는 정말로 아무것도
- 그 사람들 어디갔어?!
- I don't have anything to--
- Where are our people?!
제발요, 전 그 일과 아무 관계도 없어요
Please, I don't have
anything to do with this.
저는...
I--
왜 우리를 이리로 데려왔나?
Why'd you bring us here?
부탁입니다, 저는...
Please, I--
다른 누군가와 함께 일하나?
You working with someone?
저는 혼자예요
저는 혼잡니다
I'm alone.
저는 언제나 혼자였어요
I was always alone.
푸드뱅크에 있던 그 여자는
어떻게 된거지, 가브리엘?
What about the woman
in the food bank, Gabriel?
그녀에게 무슨일을 한건가?
What did you do to her?
'이 죗값을 치룬다'
"You'll burn for this."
그건 당신에게 쓴 말이지
무엇때문에?
That was for you. Why?
무슨 죄를 지은거지
가브리엘?
What are you gonna
burn for, Gabriel?
무엇을?
무슨 짓을 한거지?
What?
What did you do?
뭔 짓을 저질렀어!
What did you do?!
그날 밤 저는 문을 잠궜습니다
I lock the doors at night.
항상 문을 잠그고 있었어요
I always lock
the doors at night.
문을 잠그고 있었습니다
I always lock the doors
at night.
저는...
I always--
이리로 모이기 시작했죠
제 신자들이요
They started coming,
my congregation.
그날 밤 아틀랜타는 폐허가 됐고
신자들은 겁에 질렸습니다
Atlanta was bombed the night
before and they were scared.
그 사람들은, 그들은
안전한 장소를 찾고 있었어요
They were-- they were
looking for a safe place,
안전하다고 느낄 그런 장소를요
a place where they felt safe.
그리고 그건 너무 이른시간이라
너무 이른 시간이었어서
And it was so early.
It was so early.
문이 잠겨 있었던거예요
And the doors were still locked.
보셨을거예요...
You see...
제가 그렇게 한 겁니다
it was my choice.
사람들이 너무 많았어요
There were so many of them
셔터를 부셔서 열려고 했고
and they were trying
to pry the shutters
옆쪽으로 와서 소리지르며 문을 두들겨 댔어요
and banging on the sidings,
screaming at me.
그러곤 망자들이 그들을 덮쳤어요
And so the dead came for them.
여자들도...
Women...
아이들도
children.
온 가족이 뜯겨나가는 와중에도
제 이름을 부르면서
Entire families calling my
name as they were torn apart,
자비를 보여달라 했어요
begging me for mercy.
저에게 빌면서 자비를 구했어요
(sobbing)
Begging me for mercy.
저 같은건 지옥으로 떨어져야 해요
Damning me to hell.
제가 그들을 묻었습니다
I buried their bones.
다 묻었어요
I buried it all.
주님께서 당신을 이곳으로 보내
저를 벌하려고 하신겁니다
The Lord sent you here
to finally punish me.
천벌을 받아도 싸요
I'm damned.
천벌 받을 짓을 한 겁니다
I was damned before.
제가 문을 닫고 있었어요
I always lock the doors.
제가 문을 잠그고 있었습니다
(sobbing)
(whistling)
무언가 있어요
Glenn:
There's something--
누군가 밖에 누워있어요
there's someone outside
lying in the grass.
사샤
Sasha.
(walkers snarling)
오! 밥!
Oh! Bob!
밥
Bob.
- 다리가
-안으로 옮겨, 나머진 맡기고
- His leg.
- Get Bob inside. We'll take care of them.
도와줄래?
도와줘, 제발 도와줘
Can you help me, please?
Help me. Help me.
(gunshot)
안으로 들어가!
Get inside!
가!
Go!
무덤가에 있었는데
누군가 날 쳤어
I was in the graveyard.
Somebody knocked me out.
깨어나보니 저 어디였는데
I woke up outside this place.
학교처럼 생긴 곳이었어
It looked like a school.
그건 그 녀석이었어, 가레스
It was that guy, Gareth.
다섯 놈들이 더 있었고
And five other ones.
아무렇지도 않게
They were eating my leg
right in front of me.
바로 앞에서 내 다리를
먹고 있었어
Like it was nothing.
모두다 알고 있다는 거 마냥 껄렁하게
All proud like they
had it all figured out.
데릴과 캐롤도 잡혀 있었나?
Did they have Daryl and Carol?
가레스는 그 둘이 차를 타고
떠났다고 했어
Gareth said they drove off.
(groaning)
너무 고통스러워해
뭐 할 수 있는 거 없을까?
He's in pain.
Do we have anything?
구급통에 약이 있을거야
I think there are pill packets
in the first aid kit.
- 그래
- 아껴둬
- Yeah.
- Save 'em.
- 안돼
- 진심이야
- No.
- Really.
푸드뱅크에 있을 때 물렸어
It happened at the food bank.
괜찮아
It's okay.
밥?
Bob?
사무실에 소파가 있어요
There's a sofa in my office.
그걸로 충분하진 않겠지만...
I know it's not much, but...
고마워
Thank you.
내가 들지
I got him.
밥이 말한 곳을
알고 있나?
Do you know the place
Bob was talking about?
그건 초등학교에요
It's an elementary school.
- 가깝습니다
- 얼마나 가깝지?
- It's close.
- How close?
얼마나 가깝냐고, 가브리엘?
How close, Gabriel?
숲을 가로 질러가면
걸어서 10분 정도 걸립니다
It's just a 10-minute walk
through the woods from here,
남쪽에 있는 무덤 부터요
due south of the graveyard.
(Judith crying)
쉬 쉬
Shh, shh, shh.
열이나진 않아?
Does he have a fever?
그냥 따뜻한 정도에요
He's just warm.
짐은 우리가 떠나고
이틀을 살았어
Jim lasted almost two days
before we left him.
현실적으로 생각해야 합니다
Time for a reality check.
우린 이제 DC로 떠나야 해요
We all need to leave
for DC right now.
데릴과 캐롤이 곧 돌아올거야
Daryl and Carol
are gonna be back.
우린 그 사람들 없이
아무데도 안갈거야
We're not going
anywhere without them.
그건 존중하지만 유진박사에게
위협이 될 요소가 있어요
I respect that, but there's a
clear threat here to Eugene.
난 그의 안전을 위험 전에
바로 잡을 필요가 있구요
I need to extract his ass
before things get any uglier.
당신들이 오지 않는다면
그저 행운을 빌겠소
So if y'all won't come,
good luck to you.
우린 우리의 길을 가겠소
We'll go our separate ways.
우리 더러 그냥 걸어다니라고?
You leaving on foot?
우리가 저 개같은 버스를 직접 고쳤소만
We fixed that
damn bus ourselves.
우리가 훨씬 사람이 많은데
There are a lot more of us.
그런 식으로 나오시겠다?
그럼 같이 가자고?
You want to keep it that way?
You should come.
캐롤이 당신을 살리고
우리가 당신을 살렸어
Carol saved your life.
We saved your life.
그래서 난 지금 너희들을 살리려고 하잖아
Well, I am trying to save yours.
모두를 살리려고 하잖아
Save everyone's.
우린 사람들을 남겨두고
아무데도 가지 않을거야
We're not going anywhere
without our people.
- 그 사람들은 떠났어
- 그들은 돌아올거야
- Your people took off.
- They're coming back.
뭐하러 돌아와!
뼈를 수습하려고?
To what,
picked-over bones?!
- 너는 아무것도
- 그 손을 어디에 올려!
- You're not taking--
- Do not lay hands!
- 아브라함!
- 이봐요 그만해요! 당장!
- Abraham!
- Hey, hey, stop! Now!
당신은 지금 당신이 떠난다고
안전할거라고 생각하는거야?
Do you really think that
you're gonna be any safer
이 오밤 중에 떠나는게?
leaving right now
in the middle of the night?
그래
Yeah.
내일은 어때?
Glenn:
What about tomorrow?
우린 서로가 필요하잖아
We need each other for this.
DC에 가려면 우린 서로 도와야 한다구
We need each other to get to DC.
함께하면 어떤 것도
해쳐나갈 수 있어
We can get through
all of it together.
제게 생각이 있어요
I have an idea.
하루만 더 머물며 도와준다면
If you stay just
one more day and help,
어떤 일이 있어도 DC로
내가 당신과 함께 가죠
I'll go with you to DC
no matter what.
알겠죠?
Okay?
글렌과 매기도 동행한다
Glenn and Maggie, too.
- 안돼
- 그럼 잘 있으라고
- No.
- Good luck, then.
난 당신들이 헤어지든 말든
관심없으니까
I'm not interested in breaking
up what you have here.
로지타, 장비 챙겨
Rosita, grab your gear.
- 아브라함
- 당장
- Abraham--
- Now.
유진 갑시다
유진
Eugene, let's go.
Eugene.
움직이라구
Move it.
- 그러기 싫은데요
- 어서
- I don't want to.
- Now.
알겠어요
Okay.
버스를 가져갈 순 없네
You're not taking the bus.
막아 보시든지
Try to stop me.
잠깐만요 잠깐만
기다려요!
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait!
이봐요 좀!
Hey, hey, hey!
당신이 여기 남아서...
You stay--
남아서 우리를 도와주면
you stay and help us,
우리가 당신과 함께 가죠
and we will go with you.
- 안돼
- 당신이 결정할 문제가 아니에요
- No.
- It's not your call.
남아서 우리를 도와
You stay, help us.
한나절만이야
Half a day.
정오가 되면
바로 떠날거야
Come high noon,
we're taillights.
끝까지 다 기다려주지 않을거야
I'm not waiting for the
other damn shoe to drop.
알았어요 우리가 같이 떠난다니까요
And we will leave with you.
열 두시간만이야
12 hours.
그리고 우린 떠난다
Then we go.
하나 좋은 점은
Bob: You know, the
one good thing
얼굴에 발길질 당하면
about getting
kicked in my face--
다리의 고통 쯤은
느끼지 못한다는거야
made me forget
the pain in my leg.
그러니까 내 입장에선
두가지 좋은 점이지
And my side, so two good things.
그 게임은 이젠 안할거야
We're not playing
that game anymore.
그래 뭐...
Well...
당신이 생각해냈던 건
all things considered,
날 좀 웃기게는 만들었지
figured you could
humor me a little bit.
(chuckles)
왜 내게 말하지 않았어?
Why didn't you tell me
그런 일이 생겼을 때?
when it happened?
나는
I knew
내가 그걸 말하면
when I told you,
이 모든게 끝날 줄 알았으니까
it'd become all about the end.
그리고 난 모호한게 좋거든
And I really liked the middle.
놈들은 자기들이 주도권을
쥐고 있다고 생각할거야
Rick: They think
they're in control.
우리는 여기 있고 우리는 자기네들이
어디에 있는지 모른다 생각하겠지
We're in here
and they could be anywhere.
하지만 우리는 놈들이 어딨는지
정확하게 알고 있어
But we know exactly
where they are.
계획을 세우면
그대로 따르지
Plan's got stones,
I'll give you that.
- 그들이 움직이기 전에 먼저 움직이죠
- 맞는 말이야
- Make our move before they do.
- That's right.
우리가 바로 오리라곤
생각 못할거야
They're not counting
on us thinking straight.
우리는요?
Are we?
결전 전에
확실히 하고 싶어요
I'm just making sure.
It's a big play.
이 사람들이 무슨 짓을 하는
놈들인지 잊지마
Remember what these people
are capable of.
- 타이리스
- 그래
- Tyreese.
- Yeah?
함께 하겠나?
You up for this?
내가 함께 가죠
I'm going with you.
너는 밥이랑 같이 있어야지
You should stay with Bob.
아니, 나도 같이 갈 거야
No, I want to be out there.
나도 같이 하고 싶어
I want to be a part of this.
어떤 기분인지 알아
I know how it feels.
But this right here,
하지만 이제는
the time you could
have with him,
그와 함께 했던 시간들은
you can't throw that away.
쉽게 잊으면 안돼
나도 카렌과 마지막을 함께 했으면 좋았을텐데
I wish I had it with Karen.
오빠가 어떤 기분이었는지 기억은 해?
Do you remember how you felt?
뭘 하고 싶었는지?
What you wanted to do?
그래
Yeah.
그런 기분이 들어서
분별할 수 없게 만들었지
It made it so I couldn't see it.
용서
Forgiveness.
용서가 앞에 있더라
That's facing it.
나보러 놈들을 용서하라고?
I should forgive them?
밥을 이렇게 해치고
우리를 죽이려고 했던 걸 말야?
For hurting him?
For trying to kill us?
오빠 뭐가 어떻게 된거 아니야?
What the hell is wrong with you?
우리한테 선택이 있다고 생각해?
You think we have a choice?
우리 전부는 아니지
Not all of us.
너만 필요한거야
Just you.
밥이 눈을 뜨면
When he opens his eyes,
네 얼굴만 보고싶어 할거야
the only thing he's gonna
want to see is your face.
받아
Take it.
- 숨을 멈추면
- 사샤...
- If he stops breathing...
- Sasha.
관자놀이를 찔러
...you put it
through his temple.
그게 밥이 원하는 걸 거야
That's what Bob would want.
(lock clicks)
(tapping)
(walkers snarling)
이봐 우리가 여기 올거란 거 알고 있잖아
Gareth: Well, I guess
you know we're here.
우린 너네가 여기 있는걸 알지
And we know you're here.
우리 무장도 했다고
And we're armed.
그러니까 이제 숨어봐야지 싶은데
So there's really no point
in hiding anymore.
너희들을 지켜봐와서
We've been watching you.
누가 여기 있는지 알아
We know who's here.
이곳엔 밥이랑
There's Bob,
아직 그대로 놔뒀다면 말이야
unless you've put him
out of his misery already.
유진이랑
And Eugene.
로지타
Rosita.
마틴의 좋은 친구인 타이리스
Martin's good friend Tyreese.
칼도 있고
Carl.
주디스
Judith.
릭이랑 나머지들이 빠져나갔지
Rick and the rest walked out
총을 많이 가져가던데
with a lot of your guns.
있지, 난 너희가 모두 다
어디에 있는지 모르긴 하는데
Listen, we don't know
where you all are,
여기가 그렇게 큰 곳은 아니잖아
but this isn't a big place.
더 고통스러워지기 전에
So let's just stop this now
이제 그만하자고
before things get more painful
than they need to be.
(rattling)
봐봐, 이 문 두개 중에서
한곳에 너희가 숨은걸 알아
Look, you're behind
one of these two doors
그리고 우리에겐 이 두 문을
다 박살낼 화력이 있어
and we have more than enough
firepower to take down both.
그런걸 너희 모두 바라는거라고
생각하진 않아
Can't imagine that's
what you all want.
(cocks gun)
신부님은 어떻게 생각하십니까?
How about the priest?
신부님 당신이 우릴 도와주신다면
Father, you help us
wrap this up,
당신을 여기서 살려는 드릴게
we'll let you walk away
from this.
그냥 문 열고 가면 돼
Just open the door
and you can go.
아기를 데려가도 되고
You can take the baby with you.
어때?
What do you say?
(Judith crying)
이젠 나도 모르겠다
우리가 아기까지 접수해도 되나본데
I don't know.
Maybe we'll keep the kid.
이제부터 아기가 좋아질 것 같다
I'm starting to like this girl.
It's your last chance right now
to tell us you're coming out.
이게 조용히 걸어 나올 수 있는 마지막 기회야
Are we done?
다 한거야?
We'll hit the hinges.
경첩을 쏜다
(silenced gunshots)
Rick:
Put your guns on the floor.
총 바닥에 버려
Rick, we'll fire right into that office.
So you lower your gun--
릭 저 방을 향해 총을 쏘기 전에
당장 네 총을 내려...
- (silenced gunshot)
- Ah!
(whimpering)
Put your guns
on the floor and kneel.
총 버리고 바닥에
무릎 꿇으라고 했지
Do what he says.
시키는대로 해
Martin, there's no choice here.
마틴 지금은 방법이 없어
Yeah, there is.
아니 있어
Want to bet?
있는지 내기할까?
(Gareth gasping)
No point in begging, right?
빌어도 소용없겠지? 그치?
No.
없어
Still, you could have
killed us when you came in.
돌아와서 바로 우릴 죽일 수도
있었을텐데 지금까지 기다렸어
There had to be
a reason for that.
분명 이유가 있었을 텐데
We didn't want
to waste the bullets.
총알을 낭비하고 싶지 않았거든
We used to help people.
우리도 처음엔 사람들을 도왔었어
We saved people.
사람들을 구해줬다고
Things changed.
They came in and--
모든게 변해버려서
놈들이 오고 난 후에
(groans)
After that...
그 후에는...
I know that you've been out
there, but I can see it.
네가 밖에서 얼마나 오래
떠돌아 다녔는지는 알아
You don't know
what it is to be hungry.
하지만 넌
진정한 배고픔이 뭔지 몰라
You don't have to do this.
이럴 필요는 없잖아
We can walk away.
그냥 가도록 해준다면
And we will never
cross paths again.
다시는 마주치지 않을거야
I promise you.
약속하지
But you'll cross someone's path.
그래도 넌 다른 사람들과 마주치겠지?
You'd do this to anyone,
그리고 그게 누구라도 같은 짓을 하겠지?
right?
그치?
Besides,
그리고
I already made you a promise.
약속은 이미 내가 먼저 했지
No!
(people screaming)
It could have been us.
우리가 당했을 수도 있어
Yeah.
맞아요
This is the Lord's house.
여긴 주님의 집입니다
No.
아니요
It's just four walls and a roof.
그냥 벽과 지붕일뿐이죠
You'll always be with us.
항상 우리랑 함께할거야
Part of us.
우리의 일행으로 말야
Rick.
릭
No, don't.
아니야 그럴 필욘 없어요
Let her stay.
함께 있게 해줘요
I trust her.
나는 주디스를 믿으니까
I'm right outside.
밖에 있을게
I just want to say thank you.
고맙다는 말 꼭 해야겠어요
For what?
뭐를?
Before the prison,
교도소에 있기 전에요
I didn't know if there were
any good people left.
좋은 사람들이 남아 있긴 했나
의심이 들었죠
I didn't know
if anybody was left.
좋은 사람들도 아직 있는지...
You took me in.
당신이 절 받아줬죠
'Cause you took people in.
왜냐하면 당신은 사람들을 받아줬으니까
It was you, man.
바로 당신이었어요
What I said yesterday,
제가 어제 했던 말은
I ain't revising it.
다시 바꿔 말하진 않을게요
Even in light of current events.
이런 상황에도 빛은 있어요
Nightmares end.
악몽은 끝날겁니다
They shouldn't end who you are.
사람들은 당신이 있는 한 괜찮을거예요
And that is just
this dead man's opinion.
그리고 그게 이 송장의 생각이에요
I'll take it.
새겨듣지
(chuckles)
Just look at her
주디스를 보고
and tell me the world
isn't gonna change.
세상은 변함없이 괜찮을거라고
내게 말해줘요
(raspy breathing)
You were out.
의식이 없었어
Hmm.
Was I?
내가?
You were.
응
Why are you smiling?
왜 웃고있어?
I think I was dreaming.
난 내가 꿈꾸고 있는 줄 알았어
And I think you
그리고 네가
were smiling back
at me in the dream.
꿈에서 나를 보고 미소짓고 있었어
Yeah, that's it.
그래, 바로 그렇게
So what is it?
그래서 그건 뭐였어?
The good that comes
out of this bad?
나쁜일 중에 일어나는 좋은 것?
Bob?
밥?
밥...
(sobbing)
Give it here.
이리줘 내가 할게
You step out.
나가있어
Okay?
알겠지?
(door opens)
(door closes)
(breathing heavily)
(squelches)
This is our route to DC.
이게 DC로 가는 우리 길이요
We'll stick to it
as long as we're able.
가능한 이 길로 가려고 하오
If not, well, you got
our destination.
뭐 몰라도, 우리가 어디로 가는지는 아니까
Once Eugene gets to the
big brains left up there,
일단 유진이 아직 남아있는
수뇌부로 가게 되면
things are gonna bounce back.
이 문제들은 다시 원래대로 돌아올거요
This group should
be there for it.
그때까지 이 그룹은 남아있어야 해요
You should be there for it.
당신도 그때까지 남아 있어야 해
They will be.
그럴거예요
We will.
남아있을거야
그럴거야
Let's go.
그럼 가지
(shovel striking dirt)
I never asked how it was for you
어땠는지 한 번도 물어본 적이
없었던것 같아서
getting to Terminus.
종착역 가는 것 말야
It killed me.
고통스러웠지
No, it didn't.
꼭 그렇지만은 않았어
(door opens)
I can't sleep.
잠을 잘 수가 없군요
And now, sitting in there...
이제야 앉아보니...
Quiet.
고요하군요
It isn't just what
happened last night.
지난 밤 일 때문에
잠 못드는건 아니에요
Saying what happened before...
그 전에 일어났던 일들은...
out loud...
더 시끄러웠죠...
I see it all again.
다시 생각나게 하는군요
I hear them.
그들의 목소리가 들려요
Yeah.
그렇겠죠
That won't stop.
멈추지 않을거예요
But it won't be all the time.
그래도 언제나 그렇진 않을거예요
(rustling)
Where's Carol?
캐롤은 어딨어?
나와 봐